<text1>Narrator:	According to all known laws of aviation, there is no way that a bee should be able to fly. Its wings are too small to get its fat little body off the ground. The bee, of course, flies anyway because bees don't care what humans think is impossible.
 	Cut to Barry's room, where he's picking out what to wear.
Barry	Yellow, black. Yellow, black. Yellow, black. Yellow, black. Ooh, black and yellow! Yeah, let's shake it up a little.
 	Barry uses honey from a dispenser to style his hair, rinse his mouth, and then applies it to his armpits.
Mom (Janet Benson)	(calling from downstairs:) Barry! Breakfast is ready!
Barry:	Coming! (phone rings) Oh, hang on a second. (adjusts his antennas into a headset) Hello?
Adam Flayman	(on the phone) Barry?
Barry:	Adam?
Adam:	Can you believe this is happening?
Barry:	I can't believe it. I'll pick you up. (hangs up, sharpens his stinger) Lookin' sharp. (flies downstairs)
Mom:	Barry, why don't you use the stairs? Your father paid good money for those.
Barry:	Sorry. I'm excited.
Dad (Martin Benson):	Here's the graduate. We're very proud of you, son. And a perfect report card, all B's.
Mom:	Very proud. (touches Barry's hair)
Barry:	Ma! I got a thing going here.
Mom:	Ah, you got some lint on your fuzz.
Barry:	Ow! That's me!
Dad:	Wave to us! We'll be in row 118,000.
Barry:	Bye! (flies off)
Mom:	Barry, I told you, stop flying in the house!
 	(Barry drives his car to pick up his classmate. Adam's outside his house, reading the Hive Today newspaper. The front page headline reads "FRISBEE HITS HIVE ! Internet Down. Bee: 'I heard sound, then Wham-o!'")
Barry:	Hey, Adam.
Adam:	Hey, Barry. Is that fuzz gel?
Barry:	A little. It's a special day, finally graduating.
Adam:	Never thought I'd make it.
Barry:	Yeah, three days of grade school, three days of high school.
Adam:	Those were so awkward.
Barry:	Three days of college. I'm glad I took off one day in the middle and just hitchhiked around the hive.
Adam:	You did come back different.
 	(a bee calls out as they drive past)
Bee:	Hi, Barry.
Barry:	Hey Artie, growing a mustache? Looks good.
Adam:	Hey, did you hear about Frankie?
Barry:	Yeah.
Adam:	You goin' to his funeral?
Barry:	No, I'm not goin' to his funeral. Everybody knows you sting someone, you die. You don't waste it on a squirrel. He was such a hothead.
Adam:	Yeah, I guess he could have just gotten out of the way.
 	(They make various noises as the car goes up and down some hills and does a loop on the road.)
A & B	Woah! Oooooooh!
Adam:	I love this incorporating an amusement park right into our regular day.
Barry:	I guess that's why they say we don't need vacations.
 	(They arrive, fly in and take their seats.)
Barry:	Boy, quite a bit of pomp... under the circumstances.
Barry:	Well, Adam, today we are men.
Adam:	We are!
Barry:	Bee-men.
Adam:	Amen!
A & B:	Hallelujah! (bumping each other) Aaaaaaaaaaaah!
Announcer:	Students, faculty, distinguished bees, please welcome Dean Buzzwell.
 	Dean Buzzwell walks onto the stage and taps the microphone.
Buzzwell:	Welcome, New Hive City graduating class of... (presses a button to change the timer on the podium from 9:00 to 9:15) ...9:15. And that concludes our graduation ceremonies.
 	(Students cheer, throw their caps into the air as helmets are placed on their heads.)
Buzzwell:	And begins your career at Honex Industries!
Barry:	Are we gonna pick our jobs today?
Adam:	I heard it's just orientation.
Barry:	Huh. Woah. Heads up! Here we go.
 	(The stands for Winger University the students are sitting in begin converting into tram seating.)
Female announcer:	Keep your hands and antennas inside the tram at all times. (flies down to go in the tram as it starts moving and repeats it in Spanish:) Mantenga sus manos y antenas dentro del tranvía en todo momento.
Barry:	Wonder what it's going to be like?
Adam:	A little scary. (he and Barry mimic shivering and making scared noises)
Trudy, the Honex tour guide:	Welcome to Honex, a division of Honesco and a part of the Hexagon Group.
Barry:	This is it!
everyone:	Wow. (tram moves into the factory floor)
Barry:	Wow.
Trudy:	We know that you, as a bee, have worked your whole life to get to the point where you can work for your whole life. Honey begins when our valiant Pollen Jocks bring the nectar to the hive. Our top-secret formula is automatically color-corrected, scent-adjusted and bubble-contoured into this soothing sweet syrup with its distinctive golden glow you know as...
everyone:	Honey!
 	(Tour guide grabs a beaker of honey as they drive by and tosses it to the group, which bounce it around towards the back.}
Adam:	That girl was hot.
Barry:	She's my cousin!
Adam:	She is?
Barry:	Yes, we're all cousins.
Adam:	Right. You're right.
Trudy:	At Honex, we also constantly strive to improve every aspect of bee existence. These bees are stress-testing a new helmet technology.
 	(Behind a display window, a bee puts on a helmet, then runs back and forth as levers holding a rolled-up magazine, flyswatter and a shoe move down to try to hit him. He is hit by the magazine, dodges the flyswatter, but then hit by the boot and again by all three, followed by being sprayed with aerosol from two cans. He signals he's okay, but is flattened by the flyswatter, magazine and shoe converging to strike him together. He signals he's still okay by poking his arm up through a hole in the flyswatter and giving another thumbs up. The tram riders applaud.)
Adam:	Ooh. What do you think he makes?
Barry:	Not enough.
Trudy:	And here we have our latest advancement, the Krelman.
Barry:	Wow, what does that do?
Trudy:	Catches that little strand of honey that hangs after you pour it. Saves us millions.
 	(A Krelman worker waves and Adam waves back.)
Adam:	Uh, uh, can anyone work on the Krelman?
Trudy:	Of course. Most bee jobs are small ones. But bees know that every small job, if it's done well, means a lot. But choose carefully because you'll stay in the job that you pick for the rest of your life.
Barry:	The same job the rest of your life? I didn't know that.
Adam:	What's the difference?
Barry:	Huh?
Trudy:	And you'll be happy to know that bees, as a species, haven't had one day off in 27 million years. Wooh!
Barry:	So you'll just work us to death?
Trudy:	We'll sure try.
 	(Everyone laughs while Barry looks uncomfortable. The tram converts into a boat that flows down a log-flume style ramp with honey in it, then converts back to a wheeled tram at the end.)
 	(With the tour over, Adam and Barry head home. Adam jumps with excitement.)
Adam:	Wow! That blew my mind!
Barry:	"What's the difference?" Adam, how could you say that? One job forever? That's an insane choice to have to make.
Adam:	Well, I'm relieved. Now we only have to make one decision in life.
Barry:	But, Adam, how could they never have told us that?
Adam:	Barry, why would you question anything? We're bees. We're the most perfectly functioning society on Earth.
 	(a filling station attendant yells at a bee for putting the honey nozzle into his own mouth.)
Barry:	Yeah, but Adam, did you ever think that maybe things work a little too well around here?
Adam:	Like what? Give me one example.
 	(both stop in the middle of an intersection. the traffic adjusts to drive around them.)
Barry:	I don't know. But you know what I'm talking about.
Announcer over speaker:	Please clear the gate. Royal Nectar Force on approach. Royal Nectar Force on approach.
Barry:	Wait a second. Check it out. Hey, those are Pollen Jocks!
Adam:	Wow.
 	(Pollen Jocks fly into the hive and land.)
Adam:	I've never seen them this close.
Barry:	They know what it's like to go outside the hive.
Adam:	Yeah, but some of them don't come back.
 	(two lady bees wave at the jocks and call out:)
Girl Bees	Hey, Jocks!
Hi, Jocks!
 	(The pollen is removed from the jocks and collected into storage capsules marked "Nectar", then trucked away. A General flies over to welcome them.)
General:	You guys did great! You're monsters! You're sky freaks! I love it! I love it!
Barry:	I wonder where those guys have just been.
Adam:	I don't know.
Barry:	Their day's not planned. Outside the hive, flying who knows where, doing who knows what.
Adam:	You can't just decide one day to be a Pollen Jock. You have to be bred for that.
Barry:	Right. (pollen begins drifting down around them) Look at that. That's more pollen than you and I will ever see in a lifetime.
Adam:	It's just a status symbol. I think bees make too big a deal out of it.
Barry:	Perhaps. Unless you're wearing it and the ladies see you wearing it.
 	(the same two lady bees giggle at being talked about by Barry)
Adam:	Those ladies? Aren't they our cousins too?
Barry:	Distant. Distant.
 	Three pollen jocks observe them.
Jackson:	Look at these two.
Splitz:	Couple of Hive Harrys.
Jackson:	Let's have some fun with them.
Lady 1:	It must be so dangerous being a Pollen Jock.
Barry:	Oh, yeah. One time a bear had me pinned up against a mushroom! He had one paw on my throat, and with the other, he was slapping me back and forth across the face!
Lady 2:	Oh, my!
Barry:	I never thought I'd knock him out.
Lady 1:	(to Adam) And what were you doing during all of this?
Adam:	Obviously, I was trying to alert the authorities.
Barry:	I can autograph that if you want.
Jackson:	A little gusty out there today, wasn't it, comrades?
Barry:	Yeah. Gusty.
Buzz:	Yeah, we're gonna hit a sunflower patch about six miles from here tomorrow.
Barry:	Six miles, huh?
Adam:	Barry!
Buzz:	It's a puddle jump for us, but, uh, maybe you're not up for it.
Barry:	Maybe I am.
Adam:	(quietly:) You are not.
Buzz:	We're going 0900 at J-Gate.
Adam:	Woah!
Buzz:	What do you think, buzzy-boy? Are you bee enough?
Barry:	I might be. It all depends on what 0900 means.
 	(later, back at home that night, Barry is on the balcony, looking out at the hive)
Dad:	Hey, Honex!
Barry:	Oh! Dad, you surprised me.
Dad	(laughing) Have you decided what you're interested in, son?
Barry:	Well, there's a lot of choices.
Dad:	But you only get one. (laughs again)
Barry:	Dad, do you ever get bored doing the same job every day?
Dad:	Son, let me tell you something about stirring. You grab that stick, and you just move it around, and you stir it around. You get yourself into a rhythm. It's a beautiful thing.
Barry:	You know, Dad, the more I think about it, maybe the honey field just isn't right for me.
Dad:	And you were thinking of what, making balloon animals? That's a bad job for a guy with a stinger.
Barry:	Well, no...
Dad:	Janet, your son's not sure he wants to go into honey!
Mom:	Oh, Barry, you are so funny sometimes.
Barry:	I'm not trying to be funny.
Dad:	You're not funny! You're going into honey. Our son, the stirrer!
Mom:	You're gonna be a stirrer?
Barry:	No one's listening to me!
Dad:	Wait till you see the sticks I have for you.
Barry:	I could say anything I want right now. (in singsong) I'm gonna get an ant tattoo!
Mom:	Oh, let's open some fresh honey and celebrate!
Barry:	Maybe I'll pierce my thorax.
 	(Mom and dad start walking away. Dad raises his glass and says, "To honey!")
Barry:	Shave my antennae.
Mom:	So funny.
Barry:	Shack up with a grasshopper. Get a gold tooth and start calling everybody "dawg"!
Dad:	I'm so proud.
 	(Barry and Adam arrive the next morning at the job selection booth.)
Adam:	I can't believe we're starting work today!
Barry:	Today's the day.
Adam:	Come on! All the good jobs will be gone.
Barry:	(unenthused) Yeah, right.
 	(Dean Buzzwell at his second job, located at the desk in front of the Honex Job Placement Board)
Buzzwell:	Pollen counting, stunt bee, pouring, stirrer, front desk, hair removal...
Sandy Shrimpkin:	Is it still available?
Buzzwell:	Hang on. Two left! And ... one of them's yours! Congratulations! son, Step to the side, please.
Sandy:	Yeah!
Adam:	What'd you get?
Sandy:	Picking the crud out.
Adam:	Woah.
Sandy:	That is stellar!
Adam:	Wow!
Buzzwell:	Couple of newbies?
Adam:	Yes, sir! Our first day! And we are ready!
Buzzwell:	Well, step up and make your choice.
Adam:	(to Barry) Do you want to go first?
Barry:	Uh, no, you go.
Adam:	Oh, my. What's available?
Buzzwell:	Restroom attendant's always open, and not for the reason you think.
Adam:	Any chance of getting on to the Krelman, sir?
Buzzwell:	Sure, you're on. (status for Krelman worker changes suddenly) Oh, I'm sorry, the Krelman just closed out.
Adam:	Oh!
Buzzwell:	Wax monkey</text1>
<key1>EINFACHLIEBE</key1>
<text2>Barry:	Well...
Adam:	Well? Well?
Barry:	Well, I met someone.
Adam:	You met someone? Was she Bee-ish?
Barry:	Mmm.
Adam:	Not a wasp? Your parents will kill you.
Barry:	No, no, no, not a wasp.
Adam:	Spider?
Barry:	You know, I'm not attracted to the spiders. I know to everyone else it's like the hottest thing with the eight legs and all. I can't get by that face. (Barry grimaces and makes a noise.)
Adam:	So, uh, who is she?
Barry:	She's... uh... a human.
Adam:	Oh no, no, no, no. That didn't happen. You didn't do that. That is a bee law. You wouldn't break a bee law.
Barry:	Her name's Vanessa.
Adam:	Oh, oh boy!
Barry:	She's so-o nice. And she's a florist!
Adam:	Oh, no. No, no, no! You're dating a human florist?
Barry:	W-w-well, we're not dating.
Adam:	You're flying outside the hive. You're talking to human beings that attack our homes with power washers and M-80s. That's one-eighth of a stick of dynamite.
Barry:	She saved my life. And she understands me.
Adam:	This is over.
Barry:	(pulls out the rum cake crumb) Eat this. (pushes it into Adam's face.)
Adam:	This is not over. What was that?
Barry:	They call it a crumb.
Adam:	That was so stingin' stripey!
Barry:	And that's not even what they eat. That just falls off what they eat. Do you know what a Cinnabon is?
Adam:	No.
Barry:	It's bread...
Adam:	Come in here! (opens the door to the office where he works and guides Barry inside)
Barry:	...and cinnamon,
Adam:	Be quiet!
Barry:	...and frosting. They heat it up–
Adam:	Sit down!
Barry:	Really hot!
Adam:	Listen to me! We are not them. We're us. There's us and there's them.
Barry:	Yes, but who can deny the heart that is yearning...
Adam:	There's no yearning. Stop yearning. Listen to me. You have got to start thinking bee, my friend.
 	(another bee joins in:) Thinking bee.
(and another joins in:) Thinking bee.
(all bees in the office begin chanting:) Thinking bee. Thinking bee. Thinking bee.
 	(Outside his house, Barry sits on a raft in his family's hexagon-shaped honey pool, legs dangling into the honey. Mom and dad approach, wearing cabana-type outfits, sun shining behind them.)
Mom:	There he is. He's in the pool.
Dad:	You know what your problem is, Barry?
Barry:	I've got to start thinking bee?
Dad:	Barry, how much longer is this going to go on? It's been three days. I don't understand why you're not working.
Barry:	Well, I've got a lot of big life decisions I'm thinking about
Dad:	What life? You have no life! You have no job! You're barely a bee!
Barry:	Ugh.
Mom:	Would it kill you to just make a little honey?
 	(Barry rolls off the raft and sinks into the pool.)
Mom:	Barry, come out from under there. Your father's talking to you. Martin, would you talk to him?
Dad:	Barry, I'm talking to you.
 	(Barry keeps swimming downward through the honey, which clears and leads him to an imaginary park where Vanessa is waiting for him, reclining on a picnic blanket. "Sugar Sugar" by The Archies is playing in the background. She swats a mosquito that lands on her leg, then looks at Barry for his reaction. Both are surprised, but then laugh about it.)
Vanessa:	You coming? (said in a sultry way)
Barry:	Got everything?
Vanessa:	All set. (She gets into a one-man ultralight plane with a black-and-yellow paint job and puts on her helmet. She and the plane are now Barry's size.)
Barry:	You go ahead. I'll catch up.
Vanessa:	Don't be too long. (The plane takes off. Barry soon catches up and they fly together.)
Vanessa:	Watch this!
 	(The plane does a loop, trailing red smoke that forms a heart, then crashes into the side of a rock pile, bursting into flames.)
Barry:	(yelling in anguish:) Vanessa! (his cry changes to bubbles escaping his mouth)
 	(Barry breaks the surface of the pool, gasping for air.)
Dad:	We're still here, Barry.
Mom:	I told you not to yell at him. He doesn't respond when you yell at him.
Dad:	Then why are you yelling at me?
Mom:	Because you don't listen.
Dad:	Ah, I'm not listing to this.
Barry:	(dries himself and puts on his sweater) Sorry Mom, I've got to go.
Mom:	Where are you going?
Barry:	Nowhere. I'm meeting a friend.
Mom:	(calling after him:) A girl? Is this why you can't decide?
Barry:	Bye!
Mom:	I just hope she's Bee-ish.
 	(Vanessa exits her florist shop, flipping the sign over and locking the door.)
Barry:	(he see the Tournament of Roses Parade poster) So they have a huge parade of just flowers every year in Pasadena?
Vanessa:	Oh, to be in the Tournament of Roses, that's every florist's dream. Up on a float, surrounded by flowers, crowds cheering.
Barry:	Wow, a tournament. Do the roses actually complete in athletic events?
Vanessa:	No. All right, I've got one. How come you don't fly everywhere?
Barry:	It's exhausting.
Vanessa:	Hmmm.
Barry:	Why don't you run everywhere? Isn't that faster?
Vanessa:	Yeah, okay. I see, I see. All right, your turn.
Barry:	Ah! Tivo. You can just freeze live TV? That's insane.
Vanessa:	What, you don't have anything like that?
Barry:	We have Hivo, but it's a disease. It's a horrible, horrible disease.
Vanessa:	Oh my.
 	(They turn a corner onto a busier street. People start swatting at Barry.)
Man:	Dumb bees!
Vanessa:	You must just want to sting all those jerks.
Barry:	We really try not to sting. It's usually fatal for us.
Vanessa:	So you really have to watch your temper?
 	(they enter a supermarket)
Barry:	Oh yeah, very carefully. You kick a wall, take a walk, write an angry letter and throw it out. You work though it like any emotion– anger, jealousy, (under his breath) lust.
 	(Barry lands on cardboard boxes in the aisle. A stock boy hits him with a rolled-up advertisement.)
Vanessa:	(to Barry:) Oh my goodness. Are you okay?
Barry:	Yeah. Whew!
Vanessa:	(to Hector, the stockboy:) What is wrong with you?!
Hector:	It's a bug.
Vanessa:	Well, he's not bothering anybody. Get out of here, you creep. (She slaps him with the advertisement and he leaves, muttering.)
Barry:	(shakes off the hit) What was that, a Pick and Save circular?
Vanessa:	Yeah, it was. How did you know?
Barry:	It felt like about ten pages. Seventy-five's pretty much our limit.
Vanessa:	Boy, you've really got that down to a science.
Barry:	Oh, we have to. I lost a cousin to Italian Vogue.
Vanessa:	I'll bet.
Barry:	(he stops when he sees the rows of honey jars) What in the name of Mighty Hercules is this? How did this get here? Cute Bee? Golden Blossom? Ray Liotta Private Select.
Vanessa:	Is he that actor?
Barry:	I never heard of him. Why is this here?
Vanessa:	For people. We eat it.
Barry:	Why? (he gestures around the market) You don't have enough food of your own?
Vanessa:	Well yes, we–
Barry:	How do you even get it?
Vanessa:	Well, bees make it...
Barry:	I know who makes it! And it's hard to make it! There's heating and cooling, and stirring... you need a whole Krelman thing.
Vanessa:	It's organic.
Barry:	It's our-ganic!
Vanessa:	It's just honey, Barry.
Barry:	Just... what?! Bees don't know about this. This is stealing. A lot of stealing! You've taken our homes, our schools, our hospitals. This is all we have. And it's on sale? I'm going to get to the bottom of this. I'm going to get to the bottom of all of this!
 	(Barry rips off the label from a jar of Ray Liotta Private Select Honey)
 	(Later, Barry's infiltrating the supermarket loading dock by covering up his yellow stripes with a Magic Marker and putting on war paint. Hector's opening more boxes of honey jars.)
Man:	Hey, Hector. You almost done?
Hector:	Almost.
 	(Barry steps in some honey. Hector stops and turns.)
Hector:	He is here. I sense it. (he grabs his box cutter as Barry hides)
 	(Barry hides behind a box again)
Hector:	(talking loud to the open room as he opens a jar of honey from a box:) Well, I guess I'll go home now, and just leave this nice honey out, with no one around. (pretends to walk away)
Barry:	(he steps out into the light) You're busted, box boy!
Hector:	Ah ha! I knew I heard something. So, you can talk.
 	(Barry flies at him, stinger first, backing him against the wall. Hector drops the knife.)
Barry:	Oh, I can talk. And now you're going to start talking. Where are you getting all the sweet stuff? Who's your supplier?!
Hector:	I don't know what you're talking about. I though we were all friends. The last thing we want to do is upset any of you... bees!
 	(Hector grabs a push pin. Barry begins fencing with his stinger..)
Hector:	Ha! You're too late. It's ours now!
Barry:	You, sir, have crossed the wrong sword.
Hector:	You, sir, are about to be lunch for my iguana, Ignacio!
 	(The fight continues. They cross swords and get nose-to-nose.)
Barry:	Where is the honey coming from? (Barry knocks the push pin away and put his stinger up to Hector's nose.) Tell me where!
Hector:	(points to a truck) Honey Farms. It comes from Honey Farms.
 	(Barry flies after the departing truck, dodging a bus, taxis and a messenger on a bicycle. One driver yells at messenger, "Crazy person!")
 	(Barry continues his pursuit, using the elastic strap on a bicycle messenger's helmet to launch himself towards the truck. He lands on the windshield, pressed against it by the wind. He sees himself surrounded by dead bugs, then works his way around them.)
Barry:	Oh my. What horrible thing has happened here? Look at these faces. They never knew what hit them. And now they're on the road to nowhere.
 	(a mosquito opens his eyes) Psst! Just keep still.
Barry:	What? You're not dead?
Mooseblood:	Do I look dead? Hey man, they will wipe anything that moves. Now, where you headed?
Barry:	To Honey Farms. I am onto something huge here.
Mooseblood:	I'm going to Alaska. Moose blood. Crazy stuff. Blows your head off.
Ladybug:	I'm going to Tacoma.
Barry:	(to a fly:) What about you?
Mooseblood:	He really is dead.
Barry:	All right.
 	(the driver's hand moves to the windshield wiper lever)
Mooseblood:	Uh oh.
Barry:	What is that?
Mooseblood:	Oh no! It's a wiper, triple blade!
Barry:	Triple blade?
Mooseblood:	Jump on. It's your only chance, bee.
 	(They hang onto the wiper as it moves back and forth. Mooseblood yells at the driver through the glass)
Mooseblood:	Why does everything have to be so dog-gone clean?! How much do you people need to see? Open your eyes! Stick your head out the window!
 	(inside the cab, the radio's playing)
Announcer:	For NPR News in Washington, I'm Carl Kasell.
Mooseblood:	But don't kill no more bugs! (he is flung off the wiper as the washer fluid sprays onto the windshield) Beeeeeeeee!
Barry:	Moose blood guy!
 	(Barry gets flung off, grabs ahold of the radio antenna. A cricket flying by grabs ahold of the antenna. Both scream simultaneously.)
Driver:	You hear something?
Passenger:	Like what?
Driver:	Like tiny screaming.
Passenger:	Turn off the radio.
 	(The driver turns off the radio and the antenna retracts. As it lowers, the cricket and Barry work their way to its top. Barry wins and the cricket has to let go, but then so does Barry, and he's sucked into the air horn on the top of the truck.)
Mooseblood:	Hey, what's up, bee boy?
Barry:	Hey, Blood!
 	(inside the truck horn, later during the drive)
Barry:	...and it was just an endless row of honey jars as far as the eye could see.
Mooseblood:	Wow.
Barry:	So I'm just assuming wherever this honey truck goes, that's where they're getting it. I mean, that honey's ours!
Mooseblood:	Bees hang tight.
Barry:	Well, we're all jammed in there. It's a close community.
Mooseblood:	Not us, man. We're on our own. Every- every mosquito is on his own.
Barry:	But what if you get in trouble?
Mooseblood:	Trouble? You're a mosquito. You're in trouble! Nobody likes us. They're just all smackin'. People see a mosquito, smack, smack!
Barry:	At least you're out in the world. You must meet a lot of girls.
Mooseblood:	Mosquito girls try to trade up, get with a moth, dragonfly.... Mosquito girl don't want no mosquito.
 	(A bloodmobile passes them.)
Mooseblood:	Whoa, you have got to be kidding me. Mooseblood's about to leave the building. So long bee. (he leaves and jumps onto the other vehicle, saying to the bugs on its windshield:) Hey guys. I knew I'd catch you all down here. Did you bring your crazy straws?
 	(At Honey Farms, the truck stops. Barry flies out of the horn and lands on the nose of the truck. Two beekeepers walk around the back side of the gift shop. Barry follows, landing in a tree.)
Freddy:	...then we throw it in some jars, slap a label on it. It's pretty much pure profit.
Barry:	What is this place?
Elmo:	A bee's got a brain the size of a pinhead.
Freddy:	They are pinheads.
 	(both laugh and Elmo says, "Pinhead". Freddy opens a smoker box after they arrive)
Freddy:	Hey, check out the new smoker.
Elmo:	Oh, sweet. That's the one you want.
Freddy:	The Thomas 3000.
Barry:	Smoker?
Freddy:	Ninety puffs a minute, semi-automatic. Twice the nicotine, all the tar. (both laugh again)
Freddy:	Couple of breaths of this, knocks them right out. They make the honey, and we make the money.
 	(Barry flies onto Freddy's hat and onto the brim.)
Elmo:	"They make the honey, and we make the money."
 	(Freddy and Elmo walk onward. Freddy opens an apiary box and sprays it with smoke. Inside, the bees start moaning and gasping.)
Barry:	Oh my.
 	(Barry flies into the open box as Freddy leaves and makes his way into an apartment. Two bees are just waking up.)
Barry:	What's going on? Are you okay?
Howard:	Yeah, it doesn't last too long.
Barry:	How did you two get here? Do you know you're in a fake hive with fake walls?
Howard:	(points to a picture) Our queen was moved here. We had no choice.
Barry:	(looks at the picture) This is your queen? That's a man in women's clothes. That's a drag-queen!
 	(The walls separating the apartments are removed, revealing hundreds of them.)
Barry:	What is this? (Flies through the apartments and out into the open air. He hovers high above a tree, where he sees even more apiary boxes on the farm. He begins taking pictures) Oh no. There's hundreds of them. Bee honey, our honey, is being brazenly stolen on a massive scale.
 	(Back at home, Barry's talking with his parents, Adam and Uncle Carl.)
Barry:	This is worse than anything the bears have done to us. And I intend to do something about it.
Mom:	Oh Barry, stop.
Dad:	Who told you that humans are taking our honey? That's just a rumor.
Barry:	Do these look like rumors? (Barry throws his pictures on the table)
Uncle Carl:	That's a conspiracy theory. These are obviously doctored photos.
Barry:	Ugh.
Mom:	Barry, how did you get mixed up in all this?
Adam:	'Cause he's been talking to humans!
Mom:	Whaaat?
Dad:	Talking to humans?!
Adam:	He has a human girlfriend...
Dad:	Oh Barry.
Adam:	...and they make out!
Mom:	Make out? Barry?
Barry:	We do not.
Adam:	You wish you could.
Barry:	Who's side are you on?
Adam:	The bees!
Uncle Carl:	I dated a cricket once in San Antonio. Man, those crazy legs kept me up all night. Hotcheewah!
Mom:	Barry, this is what you want to do with your life?
Barry:	This is what I want to do for all our lives. Nobody works harder than bees. Dad, I remember you coming home some nights so overworked, you- your hands were still stirring. You couldn't stop them.
Dad:	Ehhh...
Mom:	(to her husband:) I remember that.
Barry:	What right do they have to our hard-earned honey? We're living on two cups a year. They're puttin' it in lip balm for no reason whatsoever.
Dad:	Even if it's true, Barry, what could one bee do?
Barry:	I'm going to sting them where it really hurts.
Dad:	In the face!
Barry:	No.
Dad:	In the eye! That would really hurt.
Barry:	No.
Dad:	Up the nose. That's a killer, heh heh.
Barry:	No. There's only one place you can sting the humans. One place where it really matters.
 	("Metro News" by Warner Chappell Production Music begins playing. The scene cuts to the title sequence of the "Hive at Five" program. The title sequence shows news events covered in the past: a Pollen Jock coming in for a crash landing with a stinger that's on fire, a protest about bee beards, and a bear destroying a hive. Next are the newscasters.)
Announcer:	Hive at Five, the hive's only full hour action news source.
Bees:	No more bee beards!
Announcer:	With Bob Bumble at the anchor desk, weather with Storm Stinger, sports with Buzz Larvi, and Jeanette Chung.
Bob:	Good evening, I'm Bob Bumble.
Jeanette:	And I'm Jeanette Chung.
Bob:	Our top story, a tri-county bee, Barry Benson is saying he intends to sue the human race for stealing our honey, packaging it, and profiting from it illegally.
 	(Broadcast shifts again to another studio in the building for "Bee Larry King Live".)
Bee Larry King:	Don't forget, tomorrow night on Bee Larry King, we're gonna have three former Queens, all right here in our studio, discussing their new book, Classy Ladies, out this week on Hexagon.
(to Barry:) Tonight, we're talking with Barry Benson. Did ya ever think, I'm just a kid from the hive. I can't do this?
Barry:	Larry, bees have never been afraid to change the world. I mean, what about Bee-Columbus? Bee-Gandhi? Be-geezus?
Bee Larry King:	Well, where I'm from, you wouldn't think of suing humans. We were thinking more like stick ball, uh, candy stores.
Barry:	How old are you?
Bee Larry King:	Well, I want you to know that they entire bee community is supporting you in this case, which is certain to be the trial of the bee century.
Barry:	Thank you, Larry. You know, they have a Larry King in the human world, too.
Bee Larry King:	It's a common name. Next week on Bee Larry King...
Barry:	No, I mean he looks like you. And he has a show with suspenders and different colored dots behind him.
Bee Larry King:	Next week on Bee Larry King...
Barry:	Old guy glasses, and there's quotes along the bottom from the guest you're watching even though you just heard them...
Bee Larry King:	Bear next week! They're scary, they're hairy, and they're here live. (he exits)
Barry:	Always leans forward, pointy shoulders, squinty eyes.... very Jewish.
 	(Nighttime at Vanessa's Flower Shop. Law books and legal forms are piled up.)
Ken:	Look, in- in tennis, you attack at the point of weakness.
Vanessa:	But it was my grandmother, Ken. She's 81.
Ken:	Ha, honey, her backhand's a joke. I'm not going to take advantage of that?
Barry:	Quiet, please. Actual work going on here.
Ken:	Is that that same bee?
Barry:	Yes it is.
Vanessa:	I'm helping him sue the human race.
Ken:	Wha?
Barry:	(enters room, sees Ken) Oh, hello.
Ken:	Hello, bee.
Vanessa:	This is Ken.
Barry:	Yeah, I remember you. Timberland, size ten and a half. Vibram sole, I believe.
Ken:	Why does he talk again, hun?
Vanessa:	Listen, you better go because we're really busy working.
Ken:	But it's our yogurt night.
Vanessa:	(she pushes him out the door) Oh... bye bye.
Ken:	(from outside the now-closed door) Why is yogurt night so difficult?
Vanessa:	Oh you poor thing, you two have been at this for hours.
Barry:	Yes, and Adam here has been a huge help.
 	(Adam is asleep inside an empty Cinnabon box, covered in frosting and muttering in his sleep about it.)
Vanessa:	(referring to the coffee:) How many sugars?
Barry:	Just one. I try not to use the competition. Ooh! So, why are you helping me, anyway?
Vanessa:	Bees have good qualities.
Barry:	(speaking in Italian for some reason) Si, certo.
Vanessa:	And it feels good to take my mind off the shop. I don't know why, instead of flowers, people are giving balloon bouquets now.
Barry:	Yeah, those are great... if you're three.
Vanessa:	And artificial flowers.
Barry:	Oh, those just get me psychotic!
Vanessa:	Yeah, me too.
Barry:	The bent stingers, the pointless pollination.
Vanessa:	Bees must hate those fake plastic things.
Barry:	There's nothing worse than a daffodil that's had work done.
Vanessa:	Well, maybe this could make up for it a little bit.
 	(they exit the flower shop and go to the mailbox)
Vanessa:	You know, Barry, this lawsuit is a pretty big deal.
Barry:	I guess.
Vanessa:	Are you sure that you want to go through with it?
Barry:	Am I sure? When I'm done with the humans, they won't be able to say, "Honey, I'm home," without paying a royalty.
 	(Outside the courthouse, a reporter begins her segment, talking to the camera.)
Reporter:	Sarah, it's an incredible scene here in downtown Manhattan where all eyes and ears of the world are anxiously waiting, because for the first time in history, we're going to hear for ourselves if a honey bee can actually speak.
 	(Inside, Barry, Vanessa and Adam sit at a table.)
Vanessa:	What have we gotten into here, Barry?
Barry:	I don't know, but it's pretty big, isn't it?
Adam:	I can't believe how many humans don't have to be at work during the day.
Barry:	Hey, you think these billion dollar multinational food companies have good lawyers?
 	(Back outside the courthouse, a policeman announces though a megaphone, "Folks, everybody needs to stay behind the barricade." A very expensive car drives up with a license plate saying "ALIBUY" and the initials LTM on the hood ornament. The lawyer gets out, sees a bug and steps on it. Inside, Barry shudders.)
Vanessa:	What's the matter?
Barry:	I don't know. I just got a chill.
Layton T. Montgomery:	Well, if it isn't the B-Team.. (waves a honey packet he picked up from the saucer holding his drink) Any of you boys work on this? (he chuckles)
Bailiff:	All rise! The Honorable Judge Bumbleton presiding.
Judge Bumbleton:	All right... Case number 4475, Superior Court of New York. Barry Bee Benson vs. the honey industry, is now in session. Mr. Montgomery, you're representing the five major food companies, collectively.
Layton:	A privilege.
Judge:	Ah, Mr. Benson. You are representing all bees of the world?
 	(Inside and outside the courtroom, everyone leans forwards, waiting to hear what he will say.)
Barry:	Bzzz bzzz bzzz bzz bzzz bz bz bz bzzz bzzz...Ahh, I'm kidding, I'm kidding. Yes, your honor. We are ready to proceed.
Judge:	And Mr. Montgomery, your opening statement, please.
Layton:	(clears throat and speaks in a very heavy and exaggerated Southern drawl) Ladies and gentlemen of the jureeaaaahhh. My grandmother was a simple woman. Born on a farm, she believed it was man's divine right to benefit from the bounty of nature Go-w-od put before us. If we were to live in the topsy-turvy world Mr. Benson imagines, j-j-just think of what it would mean. Maybe I would have to negotiate with the silk worm for the elastic in my britches. Talking bee. How do we know this isn't some sort of holographic motion picture capture Hollywood wizardry? They could be using laser beams, robotics, ventriloquism, cloning...for all we know, he could be on steroids!
Judge:	Mr. Benson?
Barry:	Ladies and Gentlemen of the jury, there's no trickery here. I'm just an ordinary bee. And as a bee, honey's pretty important to me. It's important to all bees. We invented it, we make it, and we protect it with our lives. Unfortunately, there are some people in this room who think they can take whatever they want from us 'cause we're the little guys. And what I'm hoping is that after this is all over, you'll see how by taking our honey, you're not only taking away everything we have, but everything we are.
 	(Vanessa smiles and silently claps and the bees in the courtroom are moved by his words. Back at their house, Barry's parents are watching on TV.)
Mom:	Oh, I wish he would dress like that all the time. So nice...
Judge:	Call your first witness.
Barry:	So, Mr. Klauss Vanderhayden of Honey Farms. Pretty big company you have there?
Vanderhayden:	I suppose so.
Barry:	And I see you also own Honeyburton, and Honron!
Vanderhayden:	Yes. They provide beekeepers for our farms.
Barry:	Beekeeper. I find that to be a very disturbing term, I have to say. I don't imagine you employ any bee free-ers, do you?
Vanderhayden:	Uh, n-no.
Barry:	I'm sorry. I couldn't hear you.
Vanderhayden:	(louder) No.
Barry:	No. Because you don't free bees. You keep bees. And not only that, it seems you thought a bear would be an appropriate image for a jar of honey?
Vanderhayden:	W-well, they're very lovable creatures. Uh, Yogi Bear, Fozzie Bear. Oh! Build-a-Bear?
Barry:	Yeah, you mean like this?!
 	(Vanessa and a man enter, guiding a giant grizzly bear restrained by a collar with chains attached to both sides. They bring him in front of Vanderhayden. The bear lunges at him and roars.)
Barry:	Bears kill bees! How would you like his big hairy head crashing through your living room? Biting into your couch, spitting out your throw-pillows...rowr, rowr!
Bear:	Rowr!!
Barry:	Okay, that's enough. Take him away.
 	(Vincent stops roaring. He and the man depart without incident, leaving Vanderhayden trembling with the Judge glaring at him and Layton angrily growling himself.)
 	(Later, Barry questions another witness.)
Barry:	So, Mr. Sting. Thank you for being here. Your name intrigues me, I have to say. Where have I heard it before?
Sting:	I was with a band called "The Police".
Barry:	But you've never been a police officer of any kind, have you?
Sting:	Uh, no, I haven't.
Barry:	No, you haven't. And so, here we have yet another example of bee culture being casually stolen by a human for nothing more than a prance-about stage name.
Sting:	Oh, please.
Barry:	Have you ever been stung, Mr. Sting? Because I'm feeling a little stung, Sting. Or should I say, Mr. Gordon M. Sumner?
 	The jury gasps.
Layton:	(to his assistants:) That's not his real name? You idiots!
 	Later on, Barry is questioning another witness.
Barry:	(reading from the base of the statue the witness is holding) Mr. Liotta, first may I offer my belated congratulations on your Emmy win for a guest spot on E.R. in 2005.
Ray Liotta:	Thank you. Thank you. (he laughs maniacally)
Barry:	I also see from your resume that you're devilishly handsome, but with a churning inner turmoil that's always ready to blow.
Ray:	I enjoy what I do. Is that a crime?
Barry:	Not yet it isn't. But is this what it's come to for you, Mr. Liotta? Exploiting tiny helpless bees so you don't have to rehearse your part, and learn your lines, sir?
Ray:	Watch it, Benson, I could blow right now!
Barry:	This isn't a goodfella. This is a badfella!
Ray:	(suddenly upset, he tries to smash Barry with his Emmy statue) Why doesn't someone just step on this little creep and we can all go home? You're all thinking it. Say it!
Judge:	Order! Order in this courtroom! Order, I say! Mr. Liotta, please sit down!
 	(The reaction from the press is harsh. The headline of the New York Telegram has "Sue Bee", the New York Post reads "Bees to Humans: Buzz Off", and the Daily Variety reports "Studio Dumps Liotta Project. Slams Door on Unlawful Entry 2.")
 	(That evening, in Vanessa's apartment.)
Barry:	Well, I just think that was awfully nice of that bear to pitch in like that.
Vanessa:	I'm telling you, I think the jury's on our side.
Barry:	Are we doing everything right, you know, legally?
Vanessa:	I'm a florist.
Barry:	Right, right. (he raises his glass) Well, here's to a great team.
Vanessa:	To a great team. (both toast and Ken enters the apartment)
Ken:	(very passive-aggressively) Well, hello.
Vanessa:	Oh... Ken.
Barry:	Hello.
Vanessa:	Ah, I didn't think you were coming.
Ken:	No, I was just late. I tried to call. But, the battery...
Vanessa:	I didn't want all this to go to waste, so I called Barry. Luckily he was free.
Barry:	Yeah.
Ken:	(very sarcastically) Oh, that was lucky.
Vanessa:	Well, there's still a little left. I could heat it up.
Ken:	Yeah, heat it up. Sure, whatever. (Ken glares at Barry as Barry cuts his food.)
Barry:	So, I hear you're quite a tennis player. I'm not much for the game myself. I find the ball a little grabby.
Ken:	(scowls) That's where I usually sit. Right there.
Vanessa:	(from kitchen) Ken, Barry was looking at your resume, and he agreed with me that "eating with chopsticks" isn't really a special skill.
Ken:	(to Barry:) You think I don't see what you're doin'?
Barry:	Hey look, I know how hard it is trying to find the right job. We certainly have that in common.
Ken:	Do we?
Barry:	Well, bees have 100% employment, of course. But we do jobs like taking the crud out.
Ken:	That's just what I was thinking about doing.
 	(Ken reaches for a knife but pushes it off the table. He bends down to pick it up.)
Vanessa:	(from kitchen) Ken, I let Barry borrow your razor for his fuzz. I hope that was all right.
 	(Ken hits his head on the table as he straightens back up, then presses the apple cider bottle against his temple to soothe it)
Barry:	I'm going to go drain the ol' stinger.
Ken:	Yeah, you do that.
 	(Barry flies a couple of loops in front of Ken as he heads to the bathroom, causing Ken to shake the bottle and get cider in his eyes. Barry grabs a small section of Variety Magazine as he goes. Ken slaps his head, accidentally hitting his bruise.)
Barry:	Huh, look at that. (tears off a small corner off Variety Magazine as he goes in.)
 	(as Barry finishes up and washes his hands, Ken enters carrying a large magazine)
Ken:	You know, you know, I've just about had it with your little mind games.
Barry:	What's that?
Ken:	Italian Vogue. (he curls the magazine tight)
Barry:	Mamma Mia, that's a lot of pages.
Ken:	It's a lot of ads.
Barry:	Remember what Van said. Why is your life any more valuable than mine?
Ken:	That's funny, I just can't seem to recall that! (He whacks Barry with the magazine. He misses and knocks everything off the vanity. He grabs a can of air freshener.)
Ken:	I think something stinks in here! (He sprays at Barry)
Barry:	I love the smell of flowers.
Ken:	Yeah, How do you like the smell of flames?! (He lights the stream)
Barry:	Not as much. (Barry screams)
 	Barry flies in a circle. Ken, trying to stay with him, spins in place. There are flames outside the bathroom door. Ken slips on the Italian Vogue, falls backward into the shower, pulling down the shower curtain. The can hits him in the head, followed by the shower curtain rod, and the rubber duck. Ken reaches back, grabs the handheld shower head. He whips around, looking for Barry. There's a water bug near the drain.
Water bug:	Water bug! Not taking sides!
 	Barry is on the toilet tank. He comes out from behind a shampoo bottle, wearing a ChapStick cap as a helmet.
Barry:	Ken, look at me! I'm wearing a ChapStick hat! This is pathetic! (Ken is turning the hand shower nozzle from "GENTLE", to "TURBO", to "LETHAL".)
Ken:	I've got issues!
 	(Ken fires the water at Barry, knocking him into the toilet. The items from the vanity (emery board, lipstick, eye curler, etc.) are on the toilet seat. Ken looks down at Barry.)
Ken:	Well, well, well, a royal flush!
Barry:	You're bluffing.
Ken:	Am I?
 	Ken flushes the toilet handle. Barry screams and starts circling the drain. He reaches out and grabs the emery board and starts riding it like a surfboard. Barry steers the wave out of the toilet bowl and splashes Ken in the face.
Barry:	Surf's up, dude!
Ken:	Ew! Poo water!
Barry:	Woohoo! (landing on the toilet seat) That bowl is gnarly.
Ken:	Except for those dirty yellow rings!
 	Ken picks up the toilet brush and prepares to swing down on Barry. Vanessa bursts through the door and interrupts.
Vanessa:	Kenneth! What are you doing?!
Ken:	You know what, I don't even like honey! I don't eat it!
Vanessa:	We need to talk! He's just a little bee! And he happens to be the nicest bee I've met in a long time!
Ken:	Long time? What are you talking about?! Are there other bugs in your life?
Vanessa:	No, but there are other things bugging me in life. And you're one of them!
Ken:	Fine! Talking bees, no yogurt night... My nerves are fried from riding on this emotional roller coaster!
Vanessa:	Goodbye, Ken.
Ken:	Augh!
Vanessa:	Whew. (Ken exits, then re-enters frame)
Ken:	And for your information, I prefer sugar-free, artificial sweeteners made by man!
Vanessa:	I'm sorry about all that.
Ken:	(re-enters again)
Ken:	I know it's got an aftertaste! I like it! (leaves for the last time)
Barry:	I always felt there was some kind of barrier between Ken and me. I couldn't overcome it. Oh, well.
Vanessa:	Are you going to be okay for the trial tomorrow?
Barry:	Oh, I believe Mr. Montgomery is about out of ideas.
 	(Back in the courtroom)
Layton:	We would like to call Mr. Barry Benson Bee to the stand.
Adam:	Now that's a good idea. You can really see why he's considered one of the very best lawyers...
Barry:	Uh, yeah.
Mr. Gammel, Layton's Assistant	Layton, you've gotta weave some magic with this jury, or it's gonna be all over.

Layton:	Oh don't worry Mr. Gammel. The only thing I have to do to turn this jury around is to remind them of what they don't like about bees. (quietly) You got the tweezers?
Mr. Gammel	Are you allergic?
Layton	Only to losing, son. Only to losing.
Layton:	Mr. Benson Bee, I'll ask you what I think we'd all like to know. What exactly is your relationship to that woman? (he points to Vanessa)
Barry:	We're friends.
Layton:	Good friends?
Barry:	Yes.
Layton:	How good?
Barry:	What.
Layton:	Do you... live together?
Barry:	Wait a minute this isn't about...
Layton:	Are you her little...bedbug?
Barry:	Hey, that's not the kind of--
Layton:	I've seen a bee documentary or two. Now from what I understand, doesn't your queen give birth to all the bee children in the hive?

Barry:	Yeah, but...
Layton:	So those aren't even your real parents!
Dad:	Oh, Barry...
Barry:	Yes, they are!
Adam:	(getting increasingly angry) Hold me back!
Layton:	You're an illegitimate bee, aren't you, Benson?
Adam:	He's denouncing bees!
Layton:	And don't y'all date your cousins?
Vanessa:	Objection!
Adam:	I'm going to pincushion this guy!
 	Adam escapes Vanessa's grasp and flies at Layton. Layton and Gammel wink to each other.
Barry:	Adam, don't! It's what he wants!
 	Adam sinks his stinger into Layton's ample rear, then falls to the floor. (again, actual audio description from Netflix)
Layton:	Oh, I'm hit!! Oh, lordy, I am hit!
Judge:	Order! Order! Please!
Layton:	The venom! The venom is coursing through my veins!
Judge:	Mr. Montgomery!
Layton:	I have been felled by a winged beast of destruction! You see? You can't treat them like equals! They're striped savages! Stinging's the only thing they know! It's their way!
Barry:	Adam, stay with me.
Adam:	I can't feel my legs.
Bailiff	Take it easy.
Layton:	Oh! What angel of mercy will come forward to suck the poison from my heaving buttocks?
Judge:	Please I will have order in this court. Order! Order, please!
 	Later, in a hospital bed, we see Adam recovering. A TV is on, with a reporter saying:
Reporter	The case of the honeybees versus the human race took a pointed turn against the bees yesterday when one of their legal team stung Layton T. Montgomery. Now here's Don with the 5-day.
 	A nurse leads Barry, who is carrying a flower, to the room. Barry thanks the nurse as she leaves. We see Adam in the bed, with an intravenous line hooked up to an IV bag of honey.
Barry	Hey, buddy.
Adam	Hey.
Barry:	Is there much pain?
Adam:	Yeah. (taps the medical button) I... uh... I blew the whole case, didn't I?

Barry:	Oh, it doesn't matter. The important thing is you're alive. You could have died.

Adam:	I'd be better off dead. Look at me. (he reveals a plastic sword sandwich pick in place of his stinger.) They got it from the cafeteria. They got it from downstairs, in a tuna sandwich. Look, there's a little celery still on it.
Barry:	What was that like to sting someone?
Adam:	I can't explain it. It was all... all adrenaline and then... and then ecstasy!
Barry:	(awkwardly) All right.

Adam:	You think that was all a trap?
Barry:	Of course. I'm sorry. I flew us right into this. What were we thinking? Look at us. We're just a couple of bugs in this world.

Adam:	What do you think the humans will do to us if they win?
Barry:	I don't know.
Adam:	I hear they put the roaches in motels. That doesn't sound so bad.
Barry:	Adam, they check in, but they don't check out!</text2>
<key2>VERTRAUEN</key2>